Cynthia Connolly Collection 170
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Cynthia Connolly Collection
1987-1992
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Connolly, Cynthia
170
3.5 Linear feet
4 Boxes
Arrangement
Series I: Flyers, 3 linear feet, (1987-1992; undated) This series contains flyers for concerts, performances, and special events held at d.c. space and other local venues. This series also contains calendars, catering advertisements and menus, and additional promotional materials for d.c. space. Arranged alphabetically by subject heading. Subseries 1: d.c. space flyers This subseries contains flyers from events held at d.c. space. This subseries includes mock-up and final versions of flyers with artwork created by Cynthia Connolly, Vivian Van Praet, and Bess Powell (Taylor). Subseries 2: Other venues This subseries contains flyers from events held at other venues. Series 2: Working files, 0.25 linear feet (1987-1992; undated) This series includes correspondence, copies of newspapers that contain advertisements for d.c. space, blank performance agreement forms, zines, and a d.c. space ink stamp used by Cynthia Connolly while working for the venue. Arranged alphabetically by subject heading. Series 3: Zines, 0.25 linear feet (1987-1990 and undated) This series includes four zines collected by Cynthia Connolly. The Crack D.C., and Pit Magazine zines contain advertisements for d.c. space.
Biographical / Historical
Cynthia Connolly is a photographer, artist, and curator. She became involved in the punk scene in the District in the mid-1980s. From 1986-1992, Connolly worked for d.c. space, located at 7th Street NW and E Street NW as the Director of Entertainment, Public Relations, and Art Curator. d.c. space was a Washington, D.C. music and arts venue that hosted local, national, and international concerts; film screenings; live theatre; poetry readings; and other performances. Punk bands and avant-garde artists whose styles were not especially suited for large commercial venues found a home in the small club. Connolly was responsible for booking performances, negotiating contracts with artists, promoting events through radio and printed advertisements, and distributing flyers. She remained in this role until d.c. space closed December 31, 1991. Connolly was one of the first employees of the independent punk music label, Dischord Records, located in Arlington, Virginia, where she was the Director of Public Relations and Promotions, from 1992 to 2002. In this position, she oversaw and managed the promotions department, created advertising for print media, radio stations, and websites, among other duties. Perhaps Connolly is most known for her cover art design for Minor Threat's album, Out of Step. She also served as one of the editors, with Sharon Cheslow and Leslie Clague, of Banned in DC: Photos and Anecdotes From the D.C. Punk Underground (79–85), published n 1988, through her small press Sun Dog Propaganda. Banned in DC documented the early hardcore punk scene in Washington, D.C., including bands like Bad Brains and Minor Threat. Since it was first published, Banned in DC has had seven editions. Connolly's photography is included in the collections of the J. Paul Getty Museum, Smithsonian Museum of American History, National Museum of Women in the Arts, the Corcoran Gallery of Art, and private collections. As of 2019 Connolly serves as Special Projects Curator at the Arlington Arts Center, and resides in Arlington, Virginia.
Custodial History
The collection was donated by Cynthia Connolly, 2015.
Related Materials
Internal collections include those from the D.C.PL Punk Archive: John Davis Collection No. 175 Eddie Janney Collection No. 181 Rachel Sengers Collection No. 173 Cynthia Uleman Collection No. 176 Related external collections include Cynthia Connolly's donation of several books and postcard sets to the Michelle Smith Performing Arts Library, at the University of Maryland. Additionally, Maryland's D.C. Punk and Indie Fanzine Collection includes zines featuring Connolly's photography. https://archives.lib.umd.edu/repositories/4/resources/411 Collection 0195-SCPA
Scope and Contents
The collection contains flyers for musical performances and events, and general promotional flyers. Additional materials include correspondence, newspapers, zines, and other files Connolly accumulated while booking artists, and promoting events for the Washington, D.C. music and arts venue, d.c. space.
Zines; Ephemera; Correspondence; Punk rock music; Music
- Series 1: Fliers, 1987-1992; 3 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains fliers for concerts, performances, and special events held at d.c. space and other local venues. This series also contains calendars, catering advertisements and menus, and additional promotional materials for d.c. space. Arranged alphabetically by subject heading.
  - Subseries 1: d.c. space fliers, 1987-1992
    This subseries contains fliers from events held at d.c. space. This subseries includes mock-up and final versions of fliers with artwork created by Cynthia Connolly, Vivian Van Praet, and Bess Powell (Taylor).
    - Bands - #0 - 9, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bands - A, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      All Mighty Senators, Alternatives, Avarice
    - Bands - B, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Beat Happening, Bellsof..., The Brood
    - Bands - C, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Carnival of Souls, Crungehouse, The Cynics
    - Bands - D, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      DateBait, DeadEddie, DroolingZoomers
    - Bands - E, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Eight Ball, Esmirelda, Essentials
    - Bands - F, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Fidelity Jones, The Flying Shards, The Four of Us
    - Bands - G, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Glass Eye, Goto Blazes, Guilt Combo
    - Bands - H, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      The Haigs, High Five, Honor Role
    - Bands - I, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Ignition, Ill Humor, Interval
    - Bands - J, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Jawbox, Jackhammer Orchestra, The Julian Experience
    - Bands - K, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Pete Kennedy, King Face, Killdozer
    - Bands - L, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Laughing Hyenas, Liquid Boy, Lungfish
    - Bands - M, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Roger Miller, Mother May I, The Motor Morons
    - Bands - N, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      The Nation of Ulysses, Neverman, Nice Strong Arm
    - Bands - O, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Oblivion, Oby - 1
    - Bands - P, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Parasite, Powderburns, Psychochuckles
    - Bands - Q, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Quadracycles
    - Bands - R, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Raincrow, The Rhomboids, Rude Buddha
    - Bands - S, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Senator Flux, Severin, The Slim Jims
    - Bands - T, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Testicular Momentum, Thundercats, Too Much Joy
    - Bands - U, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Ulysses, The Unrest, Urge Overkill
    - Bands - V (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Velocity Girl, Versus, Vile Cherubs
    - Bands - W, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Weatherhead, White Zombie, Windmill Saxophone Quartet
    - Bands - X (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Empty
    - Bands - Y (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bands - Z (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Zero Pop, Zug Zug
    - Bands - oversize, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Calendars, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Calendars, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Calendars, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Calendars, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Calendars, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Calendars - oversize, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Comedyshows (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Filmscreenings, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Menus and catering (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Menus and catering - oversize (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Poetry readings, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Promotions (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Promotions (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Promotions - oversize (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Special events, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Special events, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Special events, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Special events - oversize, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Theatrical productions (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Other venues, 1987-1990
    This subseries contains fliers from events held at other venues.
    - 9: 30 Club - Dylan's Cafe, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ft.RenoPark - WilsonCenter, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Working files, 1987-1992; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series includes correspondence, copies of newspapers that contain advertisements for d.c. space, blank performance agreement forms, zines, and a d.c. space ink stamp used by Cynthia Connolly while working for the venue.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject heading.
  - 10th anniversary program advertisements, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - d.c.space ink stamp (Box 4, Folder Unknown)
  - Employee passes (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mailing list, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper articles and newsletters, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Performance agreement contract form [blank] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Phoneinformation (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Signage (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Visitor's Guide advertisements, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Washington City Paper advertisements, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Washington City Paper advertisements, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - WashingtonPostadvertisements, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Series 3: Zines, 1987-1990; 0.25 Linear feet
  This series includes four zines collected by Cynthia Connolly. The Crack D.C., and Pit Magazine zines contain advertisements for d.c. space.
  - Crack DC, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Initiated Illusions cover page (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Pit Magazine, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Wilding Zine (Box 3, Folder 22)